if you work a little bit every
если ты работаешь э по пятнашке каждый
day, 20 working days a month - that’s
день 20 рабочих дней в месяц - это
300,000 rubles Yes, if on some
300.000 вала Да если у тебя в некоторые
days you have less than a fifteen minute job Yes, you’re
дни меньше пятнашки Да вот ты на
relaxed That is, when you’re
расслабоне То есть когда ты на
relaxed you have 10,000 a day and when
расслабоне у тебя 10.000 в день да когда
you don’t strain Well, let’s assume
ты не напрягаешься Ну предположим Вот
look, if you have 10,000 rubles a day,
смотри если у тебя 10.000 в день рублей
then in 20 working days you work five,
то за 20 рабочих дней ты пять работаешь
two rest, you get
два отдыхаешь Ты получаешь
200,000 This is not your profit 200,000 you
200.000 Это не твоя прибыль 200.000 тебе
need from them for gasoline for oil for
из них нужно на бензин на масло на
technical inspection for spare parts you cannot
техосмотр на запчасти ты не можешь
earn 200,000 you are deceiving me
200.000 заработать ты меня обманываешь
You are
Вы
from the Moscow region Well, the Moscow region is a
откуда Подмосковье Ну Подмосковье это
very loose concept,
очень растяжимое понятие
more specifically, the city of Pushkin Pushkin understood and
конкретнее город Пушкин Пушкина понял а
in honor of whom it is
в честь кого он
named Well, I don’t tell you  I can say honor to
назван Ну я вам не могу сказать честь
whom it is named
кого он назван
But definitely not
Но точно не
Pushkin Many for some reason think that
Пушкина Многие почему-то думают что
Pushkin is not here in his  time there lived
Пушкина нет здесь в своё время жили
Gunners, people who
Пушкари люди которые
dealt with guns. Well, this goes on
имели дело с пушками Ну это дальше
further if you dig into it, that is, it’s not about
дальше если копаться то есть здесь дело
the guns, but the point is about those people of the industrialist
пушки А дело в тех людях промышленника
who developed here,
которые здесь развивались
masters of the cannon business. That’s
мастера пушечного дела Вот так
absolutely true. That’s roughly what came not
совершенно верно Вот примерно пошло не
from Pushkin, our classic the Great, but
от Пушкина нашего классика Великого а
precisely this  masters of Pushkin's work Yes,
именно вот мастеров Пушкинского дела Да
absolutely interesting, yes And what is it famous for?
совершенно интересно да И чем славится
What is the most interesting cannon made
там Какую самую интересную пушку сделали
in your
в вашей
village, what is it
селении чем
famous for? Well, where do you have it or not? Oh, I don’t know,
слави Ну сде у вас или нет Ой не знаю
Tsar Neva Oh, you’re in a taxi  you work As I
царь Ой вы в такси работаете Я так
understand it
понимаю
Yes Listen How it is
Да Слушайте Как
now, in comparison because of the war Yes
сейчас вот в сравнении из-за войны Да
Almost 3 years of a full-scale invasion have passed,
Прошло уже почти 3 года полномасштабного
how is it now easier to tax it
вторжения как сейчас легче таксовать
has become
стало
worse, look, I’ll tell you honestly now, that’s
хуже смотрите я вам сейчас скажу честно
when exactly the
вот когда именно было
year began
год начался
and when the hostilities began, let’s say it
да когда начались боевые действия скажем
was a year  I’m talking about taxis I’m not
так год был я про такси говорю я не
talking Ask about taxis I’m interested yes the
говорю Проси про такси мне интересно да
decline was insignificant
упадок был незначительный
you know it as a taxi driver you feel it But
знаете ты его как таксист ощущаешь Но
it’s like
это как
everyday life
бытом го
Ros further further further now it’s like
Рось дальше дальше дальше сейчас как бы
well,
ну в
overall damn I have no complaints let’s put it this way But
целом блин меня нет жалоб скажем так А
it’s interesting but in d  in the second year,
вот интересно а в д втором году из-за
why was there a decline? That fewer people
чего упадок был что меньше люди на такси
started taking taxis because of the war. What
начали ездить изза войны Что там
happened there? I don’t know. You know, in the second
случилось Не знаю Вы знаете в д втором
year, a lot happened, besides the fact
году очень много произошло помимо того
that not only the price of a
что не только цена
SS taxi
такси СС
for repairs; for auto parts; if I
на ремонт на автозапчасти если я масло
bought oil for 2000 rubles  then at one fine
покупал за 2000 руб то в один прекрасный
moment I began to I had to bathe for
момент я стал мне пришлось купать за
6,000 rubles for pain Well, actually Yes it
6000 руб ра боль Ну ну фактически Да это
was It was yes it was the peak which,
было Это было да это был пик который вот
as if the main thing is not to panic,
как бы главное не попадаться в панику
then he quietly slept That is, it
потом он потихонечку спал То есть это
was like that  there was such a moment Peak and
был такой был такой момент Пика та а
then chpok and now, for example, at
потом чпок и сейчас например вот на
this stage of today. Yes, if
данном этапе сегодняшнего дня Да если
you take that day, then in principle for
взять с тем днём то в принципе по
servicing cars with spare parts and so
обслуживанию автомобилей запчастям и так
on. In general, it’s not far from what and how much
далее В целом не далеко у что да сколько
oil costs oil How much do you buy and
масло стоит масло Почем покупаете а
oil now How much
масло теперь Почём
buy, look at the oil, I take for example
покупаете смотрите масло я беру например
syntek there for 25,000 and for your
синтек там за 25000 да на на свой
engine today
двигатель на сегодняшний день
Yes, but then when it all jumped out
Да вот а тогда когда это всё выскочил
there it took off so I had to eva,
там взлетело так что мне пришлось е ва
then you took the oil that  it cost
вот вы тогда брали масло которое стоило
2000 And now it’s 2500 Yes, now I
2000 И сейчас оно 2500 Да сейчас я
’m back to the same one That is, now I
вернулось на одну и ту же То есть сейчас
’ll say this: everything came back where we
скажу так вернулось всё с чего
started and came more and
начинались тому и пришли всё
more, it turns out that the wages have gone up,
больше получается зар поднялись
look at the prices, what’s the point of motor
смотрите цены к чему к автомобильному
transport or in general oil oil oil Well,
транспорту или вообще маслу маслу мас Ну
in principle, yes Well  maybe it
в принципе да Ну может максимум на 200
became more expensive by a maximum of 200 rubles, it’s cool, it’s somehow
руб стало дороже прикольно как-то
interesting, that is, salaries kept
интересно то есть зарплаты всё по
growing And the price Yes, it’s interesting I’m also
вырастала А цена Да интересна Мне тоже
interested, I say it was the peak when everyone
интересно говорю это был пик когда все
took off, now when is there air conditioning
взлетели ны когда там чтобы кондиционер
refill if before it was
заправить если раньше было
ptak they charge As a result,
птак заряжают В итоге на сегодняшний
today I, in principle, for 2 rubles already refill
день я в принципе за 2 руб уже заправляю
the same thing, that is, it has risen in price, that is,
тотже то есть оно подорожало то есть
prol peak everything seems to have risen in price For example,
прол пик всё как бы подорожало Например
What kind of oil What kind of oil do you
Каким маслом Какое масло вы
use
используете
cars are
машины это
imported How do I know
импорт Откуда я знаю
To be honest, I
Если честно я вам
confess to you  As for imported
признаюсь насчёт импортного
oil, here I am, this is where I live, for example,
масла у нас вот я вот где живу например
yes, I don’t know, even I didn’t even
да я не знаю я даже я Даже голову не
think about Whose synthetic oil is this anyway, even
забивал Чьё это синтек масло вообще даже
before that, I poured Japanese oil supposedly before
до этого я лил японское масло якобы до
the war  I filled myself with
войны я заливал себе японское масло
some kind of Japanese oil that was incomprehensible there, then it
какое-то там непонятное там вот потом
went overboard when the price soared Nan now
перел когда цена взлетела Нан вот сейчас
IMP, it
ИМП
turns out that you didn’t fill it with syntek before the war,
то получается синтек до войны вы не
no yes yes yes I bought Japanese oil,
не да да да это я покупал японское масло
how much did it
сколько оно
cost Oh, I don’t remember Well, about the
стоило О я уж не помню Ну примерно так
same  for example, about there for 2000 rubles there for
же например около там за 2000 руб там за
4 Lira, roughly speaking, stop stop, look,
4 Лира грубо говоря стоп стоп смотрите
it turns out this synthetic and the fact that
то получается вот этот синтек да то что
now it used to be Toda is not like the Japanese one,
сейчас он раньше Тода не как японска
it cost less, and
стои он дешевле стоил да
then they didn’t even pay for it  attention to
тогда его даже не обращал внимания на
it Yes, so you deceived me, you I
него Да так вы вы меня обманули вы Я же
asked how much it was, you said it
спросил сколько оно вы сказали оно
cost 2,000 before and now it costs 2,500 the
стоило 2.000 раньше а теперь стоит 2 500
same oil No now you have one thing
одно и то же масло Нет сейчас у Вас одно
and then you had another No, look
а тогда было другое Да нет смотрите
Then from that moment I switched already
Потом я с того момента перешёл уже Вот
Exactly, this is syntek, I don’t know what about it.
именно вот это синтек я не знаю что о на
I suspect this is our oil, yes, that
Я так подозреваю это наше масло да да то
is, syntek is a Russian oil. Yes,
есть синтек - это российское масло Да
there are problems with additives. Yes, there are
там с присадками проблем как Да там
fewer additives, and so on. Yes, the paradox
меньше присадок и так дальше Да парадокс
is that when I  I started driving it
в том что когда я начал ездить на то
regularly, I drive every 10,000 and they say
регулярно я каждые 10.000 езжу и говорят
your oil is better than before.
у тебя это масло лучше чем до этого было
That’s the Paradox of the World Cup. I think it’s funny. That’s the
Вот Парадокс ЧМ Я думаю прикол Вот оно
question. Why don’t the Japanese buy this
вопрос А что японцы не покупают это
Sikov oil if it’s better? I don’t know, you
масло сиков если оно лучше я не знаю вы
’re asking me as if I  I’m sitting here
у меня спрашиваете как будто я тут сижу
and selling oils, Christmas trees. I’m telling you
и маслами торгую ёлки-палки Я вам говорю
that we have a production plant,
к тому что у нас есть завод производст
here I am votk 5, there is a plant that
вот я вотк 5 есть заво
produces gas mother materials,
газ маточные материалы производит
Dolphin, it’s called I think it’s not
Дельфин называется Я думаю это не
Military  secret and he I don’t know where these
Военная тайна и он Я не знаю куда эти
oils go I have no idea and even in my soul
масла идут Понятия не имею и даже в душе
As they say, it’s not clear Where these
Как говорится не это поняти Куда эти
oils go But we have these oils, so I
масла Но эти масла есть у нас вот вот я
don’t know You’re asking me as if I’m
не знаю Вы меня спрашиваете как будто я
falling straight into These details,
прямо в Эти подробности впадаю вот
look I  then I just googled this
смотри я то я только что на гуглил это
oil, it used to cost 2,000 rubles and now it
масло раньше стоила 2.000 руб а сейчас
costs
стоит
5,000 syntek
5.000 синтек
Japanese and Japanese Yes Japanese
японская а японская Да японская Я уже
I stopped a long time ago in the second year
давно дца второго года я перестал вот
Delete I  I don’t even bother And what kind of
Удалить Я даже даже не лезу А какая у
car do you have? What kind of car do you have?
вас машина Какой у вас автомобиль
Volkswagen Polo something that Volkswagen Polo
Volkswagen Polo что-что Volkswagen Polo
understood? What year of manufacture?
понял А какого года выпуска
And what about spare parts in
дего А как с запчастями сейчас в
Russia now is absolutely Excellent, believe me,
России абсолютно Отлично вот верите
where do they come from? Where do
откуда они приходят
they come from? I have no idea
откуда они приходят Понятия не имею
why Because I’m explaining  I
почему Потому что объясняю я вот у меня
have a service center that deals specifically with
есть сервис цент которы заниматся именно
engines. Well, that is, they understood the center.
двигателями Ну то есть там поняли центр
Yes, exactly who specializes in
Да именно кто специализируется вот по
Germans and so on, I’m there. I
немцам и так далее я там Я им даже
don’t even ask them where the spare parts come from, they
голову не спрашиваю откуда запчасти идут
just inform me.
для меня только доносят
information in parts is not that Ponya Ponya What a
информацию частями не то Поня Поня Какая
good thing, how much did you have before the war in
хорошо сколько вот у вас раньше была в
20 before the war, yes, like, and how much
20 до войны зарплата да типа и сколько
now look like this in the 2nd
сейчас смотрите вот так вот в 2 втором
year Well, it increased by 20% for sure, or even by
году Ну на 20% выросло точно а то и на
30, specifically tell me what it was
30 конкретно скажи конкретно какая была
then and  which one
тогда и какая
now I’m specifically telling you
сейчас я вам конкретно говорю
at 20% I’m even at 20 I’m not even
на 20% У меня даже на 20 Даже не даже
lying if I roll out earlier, for example, let
вру если раньше выкатываю например
’s assume Okay, okay,
предположим Ладно хорошо на русском
I’ll speak in Russian if I roll out a
языке буду говорить если я выкатываю в
day, for example,
день например
s, then now
с то сейчас
1415 during the same
1415 за это же
time, the same
время эти же
money 30% grew like 20-30 about you, it
деньги 30% выросло как 20-30 про у вас в
doubled not in ra Well, from 8,000 to
два раза выросло не в д ра Ну с 8.000 по
16, almost none, well, look, this is with us, I
16 почти нет ну смотрите это у нас я ва
understand, we are taxi drivers, ours fluctuates.
поймите мы таксисты у нас колеблется Это
I can’t  I’ll tell you exactly this,
я не могу Вам сказать точну Вот это вот
well, look from 88,000 50% is 4,000 that
ну смотрите от 88.000 50% это 4.000 то
is, from 8 to 12 when it grew by already
есть с 8 до 12 когда выросла это уже на
50% cannot grow from 8 to 14, well,
50% не может с 8 до 14 вырасти это ну
well, let it be as you say, I’m
Хорошо пусть будет так как вы говорите я
telling you that because I once
вам говорю то что потому что когда-то я
rolled out
выкатывания
garbage now, for example, with me, I feel
фигня сейчас например у меня Я чувствую
that it is many times more included,
что в разы оно больше входит
respectively, as if I see that  us and
соответственно как бы я вижу что у нас и
prices, in principle, have increased, that is, in fact,
цены в принципе выросли то есть по факту
if you come closer to this conversation,
если уже ближе к этому разговору подойти
nothing has
ничего не
changed nothing has changed And nothing has
изменилось ничего не изменилось А ничего
happened, as if the population has declined,
упадок как бы населения он не произо
nothing has grown, we have high
ничего не вырос ны выс
salaries. How much did a car cost,
зарплаты Сколько стоил автомобиль
for example, a new Lada Vesta before the war and
например новый Лада Веста до войны и
how much
сколько
listen now I haven’t
сейчас слушайте Я сейчас пока ещё не
climbed yet haven’t looked By the way, I don’t
лазил не смотрел Вот кстати пока ещё не
plan to change the car yet Although I have thoughts
планирую менять авто Хотя мысли есть
but they’ve
но
fallen now anyway, for example,
нардо сечас упали всё равно например
I’ll explain, for example, look here’s my
объясняю например смотрите вот мой
car It was bought in the nineteenth
автомобиль Был куплен в девятнадцатом
year for 700,000 rubles there, well, under 800 is good
году за 700000 руб там ну под 800 хорошо
but it  It was bought Why for that kind of
но он Был куплен Почему таки за такие
money because it was produced in
деньги потому что он года выпуска
1919 and was bought in 1990; the
девятнадцатого и куплен девятнадцатом
car was just broken, so it does
просто тачка была битая поэтому как бы
n’t matter now. This car is on the market in
ну не суть сейчас Эта тачка на рынке на
our country.  market [ __ ] year is the same Yes, it will
нашем рынке Даго года та же Да она будет
cost lam its minimum
стоить лям минимальная её
price That is, it turns out If I
цена То есть получается Если году я
bought it for 700,000 in the year, yes,
купил её за 700.000 вот да на
today I can sell it for
сегодняшний день я могу продать её за
lam, that is, yes It would seem That is, even
лям то есть да Казалось бы То есть даже
more in this condition in which it is
больше в этом состоянии в котором она у
I now have, as it were, even more, I
меня сейчас есть как бы даже больше я
can, as it were, put forward a new car for it,
могу за неё как бы выдвинуть новый
now this car is exactly
автомобиль сейчас этот автомобиль именно
this polo, it costs Well, roughly speaking,
это поло он стоит Ну грубо говоря
under 2 mil, that is, the price there ranges
под 2 милна то есть там цена колеблется
from 00 to 00 can barely exceed
от 00 до за д может едва перевалить
look, 3 years before the war, the dollar was 50,
смотри за 3 года до войны доллар был 50
now the dollar is more than 100, it has fallen by half,
сейчас доллар больше 100 в два раза упал
that is, everything imported
то есть всё импортное в два раза
has doubled in price. In short, bro, I’ll tell you this, we
подорожало Короче братан я тебе так
go around to the surrounding area, yes, that’s
скажу мы что-то вокруг до окру ходим да
right, prices have increased, as if, for
совершенно верно цены выросли как если
example, if we take name  It’s not before the war, but it
например если взять наме е не до войны а
took a
е взять
year to buy this car.
год эту тачку можно было
Well, that is, it’s twice cheaper than what
купить Ну то есть в два раза дешевле чем
it costs now, that’s absolutely Yes, without a
она стоит сейчас это безусловно Да без
market. Absolutely right, and so in everything,
базара Совершенно верно и так во всём
all the cars are like that, yes, prices, you
все все тачки так оно есть да цены Вы то
mean  look, it turns out that the prices on the
есть смотри получается цены выросли на
car have doubled, but then they’ve doubled, but
тачке в два раза на то в два раза а
your salary hasn’t doubled, you
зарплата у тебя в два раза не выросла ты
got eight, but now you get 14,
получал восемь а сейчас получаешь 14
wait a minute, just the way I think, I don’t
сечас подожди Просто я как мыслю Да не
understand, I just think, look, if the
пойму Я просто как я мыслю смотри если
prices have doubled  times, then in order to
цены выросли в два раза то чтобы
stay at that level you need your
остаться на том уровне нужно чтобы и
salary to double if your
зарплата выросла в два раза если у тебя
salary is
зарплата
less, your salary was 8 became 14 did
меньше у тебя зарплата была 8 стала 14 в
not
два раза не
double Well, I told you right away that Nani is
выросла Ну я тебе сказал сразу что Нани
higher  I’m
выс
talking about the industry
говорю
Yes, I’m not talking about other industries, I don’t
Да я не говорю про другие отрасли я не
know how other people live and it’s not my own
знаю как другие люди живут и не свою ту
denunciation, good question is how much 20% of
донос хорошо вопрос сколько будет 20% от
rubles will be, in short, these are about numbers, not
руб короче ты вот вот эти про цифры не
numbers, you’re closer to the point, look at what the problem is
цифры ты ближе к делу смотри проблема в
now, here you are  I want to ask you
чём сейчас вот ты мне хочешь задать
a question: In what ways has my life become worse or not?
вопрос В чём стал ли я жить хуже или нет
Yes,
Да
no, it’s cool, nothing has changed, in
нет прикольно ничего не изменилось в
some moments it even seemed to be
каких-то моментах даже стало как бы даже
better. Now, if you just want to know in Russian,
лучше Вот если тебе просто по-русски ка
in what moments it became better, it’s
в каких моментах стало лучше
interesting, the work became
интересно работа стало
more, so, in short, look  Okay no  we will
больше так Короче смотри Ладно не будем
now I see you love all sorts of nuances
сейчас я смотрю ты любишь нюансы всякие
yes I am an expert in nuances
там да я я специалист по нюансам
clearly Yes I understand Look I’ll tell you this I’ve
ясо Да я понял Смотри я тебе так скажу Я
been working in a taxi for
в такси работаю лет
probably 10 years this is at least both and
наверно 10 это как минимум и то и
more that’s the only peak I can
больше вот единственный пик я тебе могу
tell you when there were problems there were
сказать когда были проблемы были
problems  There is no bazaar, but these
проблемы Базара нет но они эти были
problems were not such that you know There is
проблемы не такие чтобы знаешь Там
something there, something and a
те проб чтото и
pony, that is, a normal person when
пони то есть нормальный человек когда
he understands it when What is happening in
это понимает когда Что происходит в
the country and what is happening in general, he
стране и вообще что происходит он
understands it, he looks at it adequately and he
понимает на это смотрит адекватно и он
sees it, yes Well, that’s how it is  Well  Well, it’s
видит да Ну так оно есть Ну что ж ничего
okay Well, all this moment
страшного Ну всё этот момент
has passed, now we have reached the level we
прошёл сейчас мы вышли на тот уровень на
were at. For example, I don’t know, I’ll
который был Например я не знаю я тебе
tell you this, every year I
так скажу с каждым годом те по-русски
explain the aircraft in Russian better and better,
объясняю ВС лучше и лучше
despite the rise in prices there, Despite
несмотря на возвышение цен там Несмотря
all this crap day.  there,
там на всю вот эту лабу день там что-то
prices are rising there for oil, what’s there, I don’t
цены растут там на масло что там я не
know, they’re pushing there for this for that, Wow,
знаю там пихают там на это на это Вау
prices are rising in Russia. Here people don’t
цены растут в России Тут люди
care anymore, I’m talking about myself, I’m not speaking
уже пофигу я говорю про себя я не говорю
for the whole country, I’m not speaking for
за всю страну я не говорю за
pensioners, how much?  you per month
пенсионеры ско с сколько вы в меся
How much money per month do you get
Сколько денег в месяц у вас получается
month me How much do you get Well those in
месяц меня Сколько получается Ну те в
rubles or whatever Yes in rubles in
рублях или в чём Да в рублях в
rubles Well if I don’t work
рублях Ну если я не работаю
1.200 I mean If you don’t work then
1.200 В смысле Если вы не работаете то
1.200 Well that’s if you understand that if Well a
1.200 Ну это если понимаете это если Ну
taxi driver is  thing like this you want to
таксист - это вещь такая ты хочешь
work for 2 hours 3 hours there you understand that
поработал 2 часа 3 часа там понимаешь то
is, if you don’t strain yourself 200,000 you
есть если не напрягаешься 200.000 ты
will always earn
всегда заработаешь
in a taxi this is 8 hours of working day 5:2
в такси это 8 часов рабочего дня 5:2
so that  it’s clearer Yes, with smoke breaks and
чтобы было понятнее Да с перекура и
lunches if you want to earn more
обедами если ты хочешь заработать больше
money, the question is Is it 200,000 that
бабок вопрос Это это 200.000 которые у
you have leftover Or is it 200,000 your orders
вас остаются Или это 200.000 ваши заказы
And from them you still need to refuel to repair the
А с них ещё надо заправить починить
car and so yes, I’m talking about clean money, I’m
машину и так да я про чистые деньги
not telling you about clean money
говорю про чистые деньги не говорю вам
Of course I’m telling you  I’m talking about pure money.
Конечно я вам про чистые деньги говорю А
How much per day does it cost you to refuel your
сколько в день У вас уходит на заправку
car?
автомобиля
Well, it costs me from 1000 rubles to one and a half,
Ну у меня уходит от 1000 руб до полторы
not
не
more than one and a half if I work. If I don’t
больше полторы если я работаю Если не
work.  1000 rubles 10 dollars Yes, even
работаю 1000 руб 10 долларов Да даже
less than a liter in dollars, I don’t need to say anything in
меньше л в долларах мне не надо ничего
dollars I don’t
говорить долларах Я не
understand That is, I’m telling you in Russian,
понимаю То есть я тебе говорю русским
wait PPP, how many liters do you have
языком подожди ППП сколько у вас литров
In short, you have some funny numbers,
Короче у тебя какие-то смешные цифры е
since you say 1000 rubles how much is
раз ты говоришь 1000 руб почем
gasoline Well now  in short, look, I
бензин Ну сейчас короче смотри я
fill up 30 liters, I get
заправляюсь 30 л у меня выходит
I never pay attention to a
Это я не обращаю никогда внимания на
liter, I’ve been all my life, I’m telling you in
литр мне всю жизнь было я тебе говорю по
fact, I fill up thirty, for example
факту я вот тридцатку заправляю например
Yes, how many how many liters per day did you
да сколько сколько сколько за день ты
fall eat by taxi in 8
литров выпали ешь на такси за 8
hours look differently there is
часов смотри по-разному есть
e I’m fine, I’m not
е я Раю нормально не
lazy That is, I run out Well,
лентяй То есть я выбегаю Ну на
I don’t burn out thirty for one and a half rubles, that’s for
полторашку тридцатку я не выжигаю это
sure if I burn out thirty I
точно если я тридцатку выжигаю Я
earn money on this day so that  I’m
зарабатываю в этот день вот чтобы я
thirty liters, that is, I
тридцатку вот ЖГ литров да то есть я
have to earn
должен заработать
fifteen thousand rubles a day, so when are
пятнашку 15000 руб в день так
you 30
ког вы 30
liters? Well, count it  look, I’m
л Ну вот и считай вот смотри я тебе ещё
telling you again, the taxi driver is like this, he wants to
раз говорю таксист вещь такая он хочет
work, he wants to No, I have
работать хочет Нет вот есть у меня есть
guys who pop every day, survive.
парни который поп каждый день выжи
Look, I’m just wondering where
Смотри мне просто интересно откуда у
you got half 200, look if you work
тебя полу 200 смотри если ты работаешь
for n every day, the number of days in me
по п каждый день рах дней в ме
is if you  on some days you have less than
это если у тебя в некоторые дни меньше
fifteen Yes, here you are at ease. That is,
пятнашки Да вот ты на расслабоне То есть
when you are at ease you have 10,000 a
когда ты на расслабоне у тебя 10.000 в
day and when you don’t strain Well, let
день да когда ты не напрягаешься Ну
’s assume Look, if you have
предположим Вот смотри если у тебя
10,000 rubles a day, then in 20 working
10.000 в день рублей то за 20 рабочих
days you work two days off You
дней ты ть работаешь два отдыхаешь Ты
get
получаешь
200,000 This is not your profit 200,000
200.000 Это не твоя прибыль 200.000 тебе
of which you need for gasoline for oil for
из них нужно на бензин на масло на
technical inspection for spare parts you can’t
техосмотр на запчасти ты не можешь
earn 200,000 you’re deceiving me
200.000 заработать ты меня обманываешь
Look,
Смотри
wait, you’ve already started talking about something else  I want to
подожди ты вот уже о другом начал
talk, he looks,
говорить
okay, I’ll be patient. Look,
смотрит хочу Ну ладно я потерплю Смотри
in short, let’s take it, let’s consider everything
короче вот возьмём посчитаем всё
trivial  you want me to go through the math now,
банально математику ты мне сейчас пройти
you want to say what is the deduction for
ты хочешь сказать то что за вычет за
servicing the car or something?
обслуживание машины что ли
Yes bro Well, let’s not let’s do this, this is a
Да братан Ну давай не будем вот это
coma, these are
вот коме
deductions, you already know this, this is already the
это уж вычеты это уже знаешь это уже те
same This is a different
гово Это уже другая
situation, they change it, she asks me for a
ситуация у менят она у меня просит в
month, for example  at this stage, the
месяц например вот на данном этапе э
car costs
машина
10,000
месяц 10.000
rubles a month for an oil change, plus or minus
руб это замена масла и там плюс-минус
accordingly. I understand that in the future she
соответственно Я понимаю что дальше она
will ask me for more because
будет у меня просить больше потому что
Masha, as it were, I don’t have a lot of base, I’ll
Маши как бы я у не много поме база нет
say since the ninth year.  how I
скажу с девятого года Вот как она у меня
have it since 2004 I have invested in it now, I won’t
есть по 2004 Я в неё вложил сейчас не
tell you exactly because you won’t
буду тебе точно говорить потому что не
remember, but I can tell you that you
упомнишь но я тебе могу сказать что
know How much is the maximum Maximum How much did I
знаешь Сколько максимум Максимум Сколько
put into it after replacing the chassis,
в него вложил это по заме ходовой части
and so on and so on, well, thousands
и так далее и так далее ну тысяч Может
Maybe  100 Well, 150 is the edge, look at the
быть 100 Ну 150 - это край смотри по пр
edge, this is generally the edge, the edge is the edge of work.
край это вообще край край это работы
Look, I understand correctly that it costs you less than 100 a
край Смотри я правильно понимаю что в
month to service your car.
месяц у тебя на обслуживание автомобиля
dollars Look, it takes me a month,
долларов Смотри у меня в месяц уходит
but at this stage it’s not a month for me, it
вот на данном этапе не в месяц я у меня
usually happens. Well, about once a
то обычно происходит Ну где-то раз ВД
month, about ten times a week. I’m
месяца по десятке Я
running around, I’m eating, I’m
бегаю есть я
biting a
покус
bit. Well, about until the
ско Ну около того до
children, it’s there, roughly speaking, it turns out
дети это там грубо говоря это выходит у
I have work here.  I’ll tell you now honestly
меня работа вот я скажу сейчас честно
where I serve with work I have to
где я Обслуживаю с работа у меня
change the oil filter air salon
поменять масло фильтра воздушные салоник
there is oily, respectively, remove the protection
там масленый соответственно снять защиту
understand on the lift but I have this work
понять на подъёмник но у меня эта работа
rubles e work costs 1500 rubles Plus
руб э работа стоит 1500 руб Плюс
accordingly I  I buy all this oil, it
соответственно я покупаю масла всю эту
comes out somewhere, well, a maximum of
это где-то выходит ещё ну максимум по
three, damn it, there’s a question: Do you work for some
трёху там блин там вопрос Ты на какой-то
service or for yourself, in the sense of
службе работаешь или на себя в смысле на
what kind of service? Well, is this some kind of
какую служ Ну это служба какая-то
Yandex-taxi service or whatever it is, no,
яндекс-такси или что там ну что это нет
it’s  Yandex
это Яндекс
taxi How much did you earn yesterday
такси Сколько ты за вчера заработал
How much did you
Сколько ты за вчера
earn yesterday so for yesterday for yesterday I yesterday
заработал так за вчера за вчера я вчера
what What does it mean to
что Что значит
roll out roll
выкатать
out I’m not interested At work
выкатать не Меня интересует На работе
how long were you how much time did you spend
сколько ты был сколько ты потратил
88 hours I’ll say I’ll say I
времени 88 ча ча скажу скажу Я вчера
went out yesterday
вышел часов
1200 hours closer  by one o'clock Uh-huh Well, and somewhere at the
1200 ближе к часу Угу Ну и где-то в это
same time it closed yes yes Dada how
же время закрылся да да Дада сколько то
long did you work 12 hours in fact
сколько ты работал 12 часов по факту
it turned out on the line I was on the line for 12 hours so
получилось на линии я был 12 часов так
that is, it’s not even eight no Well look
то есть уже не восемь даже нет Ну смотри
Wait, here I am Everyone reacts like that
Подожди ты вот я е Все так реагируют все
everything is so you don’t understand guys I’m a
все так ты вы не понимаете ребята я вот
taxi This is such a thing Pony this is money not
такси Это такая вещь Пони это деньги не
for 12 hours this is money for my loafer
за 12 часов это деньги за моё лоботряс
because I had lunch 200 times went out for
потому что я Пообедал 200 раз сходил
coffee drank that is my business  forged, that
кофе попил то есть свои дела подделал то
is, by your pimple,
есть тым пыром
this is in fact in fact, if you
это по факту по факту вот если вот
look here, I’m even here for the sake of
посмотреть вот я даже вот вот ради вот
someone like you, bro, I’ll freeze
такого как ты братан я заморож посчитаю
all mine, how much I had, we
все свои сколько у меня было это у нас
have it in the
же есть это в
applications
приложения
Yes, I understand correctly that if for
Да я я правильно понимаю что если за
yesterday in 12 hours you received
вчерашний день за 12 часов ты получил
12,000 rubles, then in order for you to get 15,000
12.000 руб то чтобы тебе получить 15.000
rubles you need Isha for about 15 hours there you
руб тебе нужно Иша порядка 15 часов там
won’t get it, it’s blocked there That is,
не получишь там блокирует Вот то есть
so what about you  15 then
Так а как ты 15 тогда
you'll get it, look, explain it to you again,
получишь смотри объясняй тебе ещё раз
come on
давай
bro. Here's a man coming out Yandex Taxi,
братан Вот человек выходит Яндекс Такси
yes, that is,
да то есть вот
consider you
Считай ты
work continuously for 12 hours Yandex
работаешь непрерывно 12 часов Яндекс
allows, I don't know how long it allows you to
позволяет не знаю сколько там даёт
work, in my opinion, 12 hours and allows you to
работать по-моему 12 часов и даёт
work for 12 hours of continuous driving,
работать за 12 часов непрерывной езды
in general it's just intermittent  He’ll let you
вообще просто прерывный он тебе даст
roll it out. Well, I don’t know. Well, I haven’t
выкатать Ну я не знаю Ну ле я не
experimented even
экспериментировал ни
once. Well, I can do it in just 8
разу Ну у меня получается за непр езды 8
hours of driving. I can drive it, you know.
часов у меня езда получается понимаешь
8-7 hours I drive a passenger 8-7 hours
8-7 часов я вожу пассажиро 8-7 часов
12.000 It’s me who drives the rest of the time
12.000 Это я вожу всё остальное время
what we’re talking about is lunch
которое про что мы говорим это обед
smoke breaks smoke breaks there I don’t know there are
перекуры перекурить там я не знаю там
all sorts of things to do this second time
дела всякие заняться это раз вовторых
look at me for example when I work in the
смотри я например я когда работаю в
office Yes I do too  -I eat and so on
офисе Да я тоже как-то ем и так дальше
Yes Like But I think that’s an eight-hour
Да Типа Но я считаю вот восьмичасовой
working day It’s you who spend on
рабочий день Это же у тебя ты тратишь на
your work and 12 hours you have to
свою работу да 12 часов ты вынужден
go to the toilet you have to eat and so
сходить в туалет вынужден покушать и так
on
дальше
Yes  why I have to I’m not forced with
Да почему вынужден я не вынужден с
How much do you have? That’s in short, in these
Сколько у тебя за Вот это короче за этих
12 hours of work the fuel burns up how many
12 часов работы выгорает топливо сколько
kilometers do you drive? I’m telling you,
ты километров наезжаешь Я же тебе говорю
I’m more than 1500, not me more in my
я больше 1500 не же я больше за своё
time, look, I’m
время вот смотри я тебе
explaining to you. It all depends on you
объясняю Всё зависит от того чтобы вы
understanding  in general, who are the people in the taxi?
понимали вообще кто Люди в такси не шарт
it has 400 runs I have
встречаемся у него 400 пробегов У меня
250 and the money is the same question why and
250 а бабки одни и те же вопрос почему а
because it’s Yandex taxi Yandex and
потому что это Яндекс такси Яндекс и
many people don’t understand what Yandex
многие люди не понимают что такое Яндекс
taxi is They don’t understand at all they think
такси Они вообще не понимают они думают
it
что
exists and no one understands that that’s
есть и никто этого не понимает во том-то
all they are  Yandex is so very
всё их что Яндекс - это такая веь очень
interesting. I understood this because, well, I’m a
интересно Я это понял потому что ну я
taxi driver, that’s not me, I’m circling around the districts, you
таксист меня не это я кружусь по районам
know, I’m here. This is how
понимаешь я вот Вот как вот раньше в
people used to work in the good old Soviet times,
старые советские добрые времена люди
and they work in the city
работали да они вот работают в городе
they work in the
они работают в
city And you around the city, if you have a city,
городе А ты по городу если у тебя город
for example, the population, for example, let’s assume
например население к примеру предположим
hypothetically 100,000 people Well,
гипотетически 100.000 человек Ну
let’s say I have a city where I live
предположим вот у меня город где я живу
there and there are 100,000 people a little bit
там и есть 100.000 человек чуть
Bon
Бону
howl at addresses
выть по адресам
more than 400,000 Yes, for 400,000 you
больше 400.000 Да ты чтоли за 400.000 ты
can get there, you understand  c
можешь доехать понимаешь с Сколько
How much how much mileage do you have per month?
сколько у тебя пробег в месяц
It turns out mileage per
получается пробег в
month. Well, look, I’m telling you again,
месяц Ну смотри я тебе ещё раз говорю у
I get it, I do it once every 2  I didn’t do it for months, I did
меня получается я раз в 2 месяца делал я
n’t measure moments like these,
не замерял вот такие вот моменты прям
although I have this idea to
Хотя у меня есть такая мысль прямо в
measure it every day. That
день в день замерить То есть
is, I change it by 10,000; in short,
получается я меняю на 10.000 короче вот
now my mileage is
сейчас у меня километраж
236 Well, once every 2 months, plus or minus
236 Ну раз в 2 месяца плюс-минус
how many kilometers you travel per month
сколько ты в месяц выезжаешь километров
I don’t believe that you didn’t count
Я не верю что ты не считал
This is a good topic, a simple month, look at
Это хорошо тематика простая месяц смотри
me, not second
меня не второ ка
I
Я
run a week, for example,
пробегаю в неделю например
let’s say 5p we have 5 days a week 61
предположим 5п у нас 5 дней в неделю 61
yes, roughly
да грубо
speaking, let's multiply by 200, let's assume by
говоря умножим предположим на
200 how much you run per day per day,
200 сколько ты в день пробегает в день у
your mileage is from 200 to
тебя пробег от 200 до
200 That is, it turns out that you have
200 То есть получается в месяц у тебя
100,000 runs per month e times 200 40,000 50,000
100.000 пробега е раз 200 40.000 50.000
runs a month I can
пробегов месяц могу
last Wait, look, if you
продержать Подожди смотри если ты
work 20 days a day runs uh
работаешь 20 дней в день пробегает ээ
200 more  times how many times do you run
200 ещё раз сколько ты в день пробегает
from 200 to  250 Yes yes yes So 10 days
от 200 до 250 Да да да Значит 10 дней
10.000 Yes no Yes again how many
10.000 Да не Да так ещё раз сколько ты в
kilometers do you run 200 kilometers a day Well
день пробегает километров на 200 Ну
let’s say 200 yes then in 10 days
предположим на 200 да то за 10 дней
2000 km
2.000 км
Yes in 20 days you are shorter than 45000 km run
Да за 20 дней ты короче 45000 км пробега
in 20 days Yes I understand How much  you per
за 20 дней Да понял А сколько у тебя в
day of the month I make how much do you have per
день меся я делаю то сколько у тебя в
day how many orders do you have per day
день сколько у тебя в день
I was asked Well approximately a lot
заказов меня спросил Ну примерно много
Well how much from 30 to  n 50 orders Wait,
Ну сколько от 30 до п 50 заказов Подожди
what if you are 200 km for 50 orders, what is
это что если ты 200 км по 50 заказов что
4 km per order Yes, what about you, you’re not a taxi driver,
4 км на заказ Да а ты что ты не таксист
you just don’t understand, I don’t understand,
ты просто не понимаешь это не понимаю
of course I work in the city, you understand
конечно я работаю в городе ты понимаешь
Look, I’m explaining to you bro Here I am, I’m a
Смотри я тебе объясняю братан Вот я я
person  the one that Yandex
вот вот человек тот который Яндекс у нас
appeared in Russia, I started with this with This
в России появился я начал с этого с Это
I worked in a taxi all my life even before this
я всю жизнь работал в такси ещё до этого
Yandex city, here you go, city, here’s my
Яндекс город вот поешь город вот у меня
city, for example, it’s a kilometer away Well, how about making it
город например он километру жом Ну как
clearer for you?  explain for
тебе чтобы было понятнее объяснить
example from one end to the other so
например с одного конца на другого так
along the perimeter there are kilometers Well 10
по периметру там километров Ну 10
maximum is this Circle This is a city 10 this
максимум это это Круг Это город 10 это
is a city that has 10,000
вот город который имеет 10.000
population You understand it is not 10,000 but
населения Понимаешь он не 10.000 а
100,000 that is there is one Well forget it, in the
100.000 то есть там один Ну забей ну в
end You have a damn it’s like
конце концов У тебя есть блин это как
his internet here I measure me look at the map
его интернет вот мерю ме посмотри карту
Check everything out I take it I work around the city
ознакомься я беру я работаю по городу У
I have orders for example delivery there 1 2  3 4
меня заказы например подача там 1 2 3 4
km and the trip itself is also 1 2 3 4
км и сама поездка также 1 2 3 4
kmgu At least you don’t spin around, don’t spin around,
кмгу Ты хоть хоть не кружись не вертись
you still
ты всё равно ты
roll out when I roll out,
выкатывает когда я выкатываю это
I’m driving around the city, imagine a city that
я по городу представляешь город который
has a diameter of 10 by 10 km 300 km to survive
есть диаметром 10 на 10 км 300 км выжить
This, listen, I’m here you said 50  orders I
Это слушай я вот ты сказал 50 заказов Я
think if you work 12 hours If you
думаю если ты работаешь 12 часов Если ты
just ride for 12 hours, don’t go
вот просто катаешь 12 часов не ходишь ни
to the toilet, nothing Yes, I divided it up, it
в туалет ничего Да я разделил это
turns out 12 hours  60 minutes and
получается 12 часов по 60 минут и
divided by 50 it turns out once every 14 minutes
разделил на 50 получается раз в 14 минут
you have to accept
ты должен принимать
an order
заказ
Yes of course you that they orders one by
Да конечно ты что они заказы одним за
one that is, here you are going to order
одним то есть вот ты едешь на заказ
tebek order shpo order
тебек заказ шпо заказ
shpo And you now And what, there are no
шпо А ты сейчас А что сейчас нету
orders now because I drink beer This
заказов потому что я пиво пью Это
you're kidding bro I got it, I got it,
прикалываешься братан А понял понял да
excuse me, I'm done with my work day
извини у меня рабочий день закончи
Tomorrow is a day off I got it, it's interesting Not
Завтра выходной понял Понял интересно Не
buddy If you're so interested in Yandex
дружище Если те так интересно про Яндекс
taxi, I can tell you You'll go nuts
такси я тебе могу рассказать Ты офигеешь
there, damn it Listen, how
там блин с Слушай сколько сколько
long is it?  you're taking a
времени ты везёшь
client Well, damn, well, as for the city, I'm
клиента Ну блин ну что касается города я
telling you again Look, the understanding is the
тебе ещё раз говорю Смотри понимание оно
same Yandex taxi I don't know, you're from
одно Яндекс такси Я не знаю вот ты с
America or from Ukraine from America From
Америки или с Украины с Америки С
America, I don't know how it is there in
Америки я не знаю как у вас там в
America, I absolutely don't know, but here we are
Америке абсолютно не знаю но вот у нас
look how it’s built, I only take orders from
смотри как построено вот я беру заказы
the city, that is, I have all the
только городские То есть у меня все
trips Okay, look again, I’m just a
поездки Ладно ещё раз смотри я я просто
mathematics professor, look if you
профессор математики смотри если ты
work 12 hours Yes, you eat chickens from them
работаешь 12 часов Да из них там кушаешь
and so on Yes, let them be clean  you
куры и так дальше Да пусть чистыми ты
drive for 8 hours Yes, the question I multiplied 8 by
ездишь 8 часов Да вопрос я 8 умножил на
60 minutes and divided by 50 orders, it
60 минут и разделил на 50 заказов
turns out that the order is 9.6 minutes, that is,
получается что заказ в 9,6 минут то есть
once every 10 minutes you have to come and
раз в 10 минут ты должен приезжать и
pick up someone, this is
кого-то забирать это
unrealistic. It seems so to you, because yes,
нереально Тебе так кажется пому Да
because look  when you look It all
потому что смотри ты когда смотри Всё
depends on the order, you missed one
зависит от от заказа ты вот упустил один
moment, I’m taking one order for 150 rubles and
момент один заказ я везу за 150 руб а
I’m taking the next order for 400 rubles,
следующий заказ я везу за 400 руб
you know Look, look  I’m not talking about
понимаешь Смотри смотри я сейчас не про
rubles now. I’m saying that you still have, on
рубли Я говорю что у тебя же всё равно в
average, all orders come out once every 10
среднем все заказы получается раз в 10
minutes, someone has to sit down if there are 50
минут кто-то должен садиться если 50
orders in 8 hours of continuous driving, 50
заказов за 8 часов беспрерывной езды 50
orders every 10 minutes, stupid order, this is
заказов раз в 10 минут тупо заказ это
unrealistic, this is simply unrealistic, wait
нереально это просто нереально подожди
here  I have now I have one
вот вот у меня сейчас у меня один
phone I’m right now I would
телефон Я те сейчас пря Я тебе сейчас
give you all the computer science now
всю информатику дал бы вот у меня просто
I just can’t go out on my own pony don’t go out do
вот я не могу выйти сам пони не выходи
n’t go out don’t go out better yet  I’m
не выходи да не выходи лучше пори Я тебе
telling you, I’m making it shorter, look, I’ll
говорю я делаю короче вот смотри ещё раз
explain again, I’m working from 30 to 4
объясняю у меня идут работы от 30 до 4
orders a day, you know, I’m not 50 anymore, it’s already
заказов в день понимаешь я уже не 50 уже
3040, so reduce 50 when it’s already straight.
3040 так умень 50 это когда уже прям
Just when they do it to you as they say. Well,
Просто когда тебе делат как говорится Ну
look, why can’t I  understand Look, for
смотри а по что я не могу понять Смотри
example, they called, yes, I did
вот например вызвали да я сделал
the math, the order is in 10 minutes, it turns out
математику заказ в 10 минут получается
that for example, the order
что например
arrives below, the passengers should already
приходит зака подзе пассажиры уже должны
drop in, they don’t come down until they leave the house,
заскочить они не спускаются пока с дома
they are already standing for you  they are waiting to jump into you
они уже стоят тебя ждут должны в тебя
as well They quickly jump out
запрыгнуть также Они быстро выскакивают
and it turns out that it’s unrealistic
получается и тыну то есть это нереально
you’re deceiving me You’re just Ob you’re
ты меня обманываешь Ты просто Обь ты
fantastic That is, you want to say that I
фантасти То есть ты хочешь сказать что
don’t do 304 orders a day or something You
по 304 заказов в день не делаю что ли Ты
want to say another thing And why are you
хочешь сказать ещ вот А за что тебе
paid 400  RUB germ le
платят 400 руб зарод ле
so this increases, let’s say morning evening, the
так от этого растёт допустим утро вечер
coefficient is huge, that is, I’ll explain
коэффициент огромный то есть объясняю
if, let’s say, without a coefficient. You can
если допустим без коэффициента Ты можешь
give, for example, 200
отдать например 200
rubles for 3 km or 4 kimets on a normal day.  then in the coefficient you can pay 400 rubles
руб то в коэффициент ты можешь за это же
for the same time and for the same kilometer
за это же время и за этот же километр
so look Stop stop
отдать 400 руб так смотри Всё стоп стоп
look I caught you again it turns out
смотри я тебя снова поймал получается
Even if you drive at a coefficient of 400
Даже если ты ездишь по коэффициенту 400
then 30 orders a day it will be 12,000
то 30 заказов в день это будет 12.000
rubles 400 at  30 12000 this is the ceiling you're
руб 400 у на 30 12000 это потолок ты вот
here I'm telling you you're here you
вот я тебе говорю ты вот вот ты вот себе
're bothering your head too much you don't Well
лишне голову забиваешь ты по не Ну
look look I  mathematician, look, everything is
смотри смотри я математик смотри всё
simple if if the coefficient which
просто если если коэффициенту который
mathematician I told you initially what
математик я тебе Изначально сказал о чём
I’m telling you about, you’re calculating something there,
я тебе говорю ты что-то там
I’m telling you again,
высчитывается какую-то я тебе ещё раз
explain to you in Russian,
говорю объясняй тебе русским языком
look if I go out in the morning That is,
смотри если я выхожу с утра То есть у
I have a day off if I  I work
меня день выкат если я работаю
121,000 rubles for example I don’t take
121.000 руб например Это я не беру
plus or minus I tell you the average I
плюс-минус я тебе говорю средней Я
roll out well look how much you have with
выкатываю хорошо смотри сколько у тебя с
one order how much In short your order
один заказ сколько Короче у тебя заказ
How much does one order cost
Сколько стоит заказ один
I you  Once again I say in different ways, it’s from
я тебе ещё раз говорю по-разному он от
150 to
150 до
450, that is, in short, mostly 200
450 то есть короче в основном 200 да В
yes Mostly 200 order No, although Yasha
основном 200 заказ Нет ну хотя Яша в
basically spreads it like this, yes, that
основном раскидывает он так да то
is, he understands the coefficient. So in the
есть коэффициент он понима Вот вот с
morning you can go out in the morning
утра ты можешь выйти с утра
then later in the evening  go home and you
потом ближе к вечеру ехать домой и ты
will earn the same money that you can
заработаешь те же деньги что ты можешь
go out from morning to evening this Look, I
выйти с утра до вечера это Смотри я
understand correctly, look if the order is 200
правильно понимаю смотри если заказ 200
rubles Yes, on average 200 rubles the order will be
руб Да в среднем 200 руб заказик будет
yes then  30 orders a day that will be 6,000
да то 30 заказов в день это будет 6.000
rubles 40 orders a day - That’s 88,000
руб 40 заказов в день - Это 88.000
rubles not Well, you understand, you can, I’ll
руб не Ну понимаешь ты можеш правильно я
explain it to you correctly Look Okay,
тебе объясняю Смотри Ладно
okay Listen bro To be honest, you
хорошо Слушай братан Если честно ты мне
really
прям так
intrigued me to go to the toilet I want to I can’t Well, let’s
заинтриговал в туалет хочу не могу Ну
go, let’s go Say let’s go, yes
пошли пошли будем Говорите идти да
of course  Of course, yes, I’ll go and find a place
конечно конечно да пойду место найду
somewhere here, in general,
где-нибудь тут вообще
here you have no idea, bro. It’s
тут ты не представляешь братан Тут
just that I can’t do it anywhere, it’s
просто я не могу нигде
just that all the windows are
просто что все окна
no  the fact that the windows and just the age is not the
Да не то что окна а просто возраст не
same
тот так
Well, let's go and try, we will find it
Ну давай пойдём попробуем мы найдём
together
вместе
yes And you get the price per kilometer,
да А у вас получается цена за километр
or
получается или
whatever you look at, there is such an aggregator Yandex
как смотри есть такой агрегатор Яндекс
taxi So, forget about the Internet, in the
такси Так вот Забей в интернет в конце
end, that’s where everything is there, and
концов вот вот там всё там да там есть
of course it’s there  Of course, there are certain
конечно конечно же есть определённые
tariffs where all this is done,
тарифы где там всё это всё это делается
all this is clear, this is all bro, I
всё это понятно это всё братан я те
can just tell you one thing. Once
просто могу тебе сказать одно Вот ещё
again we return to the fact that there, count,
раз возвращаемся к тому что там считай
don’t count, subtract, you won’t count anything
не считай вычи ты ничего не посчитаешь
until you try it yourself, mathematics, of
пока ты сам это не попробуешь математика
course you have it You have a bottle in your
она конечно у тебя У тебя бутылка в
hands Yes, no, of course What kind of bottle Are
руках Да нет конечно Какая бутылка Ты
you kidding me or something? It’s just that you could put it in a bottle on the Lyuri, are you driving it or
бы в бутылку на люри ты это гонишь что
something? Of course, I’ve heard that many taxi drivers
ли Я конечно слышал то многие таксисты
use this But believe me I  not
этим пользуются Но поверь мне Я не
committed to this crap I'm an old taxi driver
привержены этой хрень Я старый таксист
old taxi drivers it's terrible under the tree Yes, but
старые таксисты трушно под дерево Да
not on the tree but there so that no one
не по дереву а там чтобы г никто не
sees where it is possible and
видел там где это можно и
should be understood So listen here everywhere
положено понял Так слушай тут всюду
in short some  at home at home you won’t find that one
короче какие-то дома дома ту не найдёшь
where Well, I live here and so you’re going straight
где Ну это я здесь живу а так ты прям
home
домой
This is my kind of microdistrict Yes you
идёшь Это мой такой микрорайон Да ты
’re going home or where No of course which
идёшь домой или куда Нет конечно какой
home You’re kidding
домой Ты прикалываешься
home if I come home I’m connected
домой если домой зайду меня связь
and where are you
а куда же ты
going in the forest But Imagine Look
идёшь в лес А вот Представь Смотри
now I'll show you how I live, I
сейчас я прико сейчас покажу вот я живу
live here, well, well, the forest
Да у меня здесь ну ну Лесная
area here is such a forest, well, we have a city all around us,
зона тут лес такой ну у нас кругом у нас
livestock May
город скоте май
236 I just realized that too  math with
236 понял просто я что тоже математика с
mileage doesn’t work out If your mileage is
пробегом не получается Если ты накаты
shorter than 45,000 per month, then it’s like since
короче в месяц 45000 да то как с
1919 Like there’s so
девятнадцатого года Типа так
little mileage mally o lura eat yes,
мало чего мало пробег маль о люра ешь да
sorry Posha
извини Поша
really good now wait, friend, I’m
правда хорошо сечас подожди дружи
literally waiting for a second Yes, I won’t
буквально секундочку жду Да что не буду
distract you,
отвлекать а
otherwise look, I bought it  Since
то смотри я её купил с девятнадцатого
1919 it had a mileage of
года на ней был пробег
30,000, I didn’t pick it up from
30.000 я её забирал не
a car dealership. Well, as it is, bro, I’m
автосалона Ну как есть братан уж
sorry in general.
извини вообще
That’s where you are.  locked up yes locked up
Вот это тебя там припёр да припёр да
yes Can you imagine, you
Представляешь А ты представляешь
say, can you imagine that
говоришь вот ты представляешь чтоль
work in Moscow has
работа по Москве тебе
pinned you down in a large metropolis so that
припёр крупным Мегаполиса чтобы так
it’s a disaster for a taxi driver?
таксисту это
Well, look, I have a car
беда Хорошо как Смотри у меня машина
bought last year,
дего года купленная
it had a mileage of
на ней был пробег
30,000, how did you open the market, you
30.000 как ты открыл ринку ты одной
did it with one hand, what?  you opened and
рукой это сделал что как ты открыл а
then closed your fly with one hand
потом закрыл ширинку одной рукой потому
because you were holding the phone in one hand. Well, yes,
что в одной ты телефон держал Ну да как
why
почему
not? Don’t you think, you think
нет А ты что не думаешь ты думаешь
differently  would have done something Why would
по-другому сделал бы что ли Зачем
M Rouge
м Руж
do
сделать всё что
anything, it’s really dirty here
угодно вот грязюка здесь правда
Well, the forest may still
какая Ну лес всё-таки может ещё в в
have entered into someone’s territory
чьё-то ти по вступил
But by the way, if it’s in something, it’s only
А вот кстати если в что-то то это только
in a dog’s or a cat’s, most likely
в собач или в кошачьей скорее всего
more  this dog is a
больше собач этот в
taxi driver, by the way, this is an option, by the way, you said something
таксист это кстати вариант ты вот кстати
about this, by the way, it’s not funny,
об этом сказа это кстати не смешно у
I’ve had such cases,
меня были такие случаи
you’ll step in and it’s even worse when passengers
сам наступишь а ещё хуже когда пассажиры
rush in and then you drive and think what’s that
вляются и потом едешь и думаешь что за
stink, yes yes yes yes, I had that one you  after
вонь да да да да у меня был та ты после
that you
этого руки
wash your hands. Listen, in cases like this, how
моешь Слушай ну в таких вот случаях как
would I wash my hands, but only I have a
бы я мою руки но только у меня есть
special
специальный
gel
гель
gel yes yes, now I’ll show you
гель да да вот сейчас яй покажу тебе
even show you the gel let’s see for yourself Yes you will
даже покажешь гель давай сам увидишь Да
see for yourself brother in such cases Yes
сам увидишь брат в таких случаях Да
because I’m a taxi driver you know  I don’t
потому что я таксист понимаешь у меня не
always have a place to wash my hands, you know,
всегда есть где помыть руки понимаешь не
I don’t always go into a store, for example, I
всегда я вот захожу в магазин например
bought something, cigarettes, something else,
да купил что-то сигареты там ещё что-то
I can’t wash my hands after that, yeah,
я же не могу после это Помыть руки Угу
but that’s all I have for that.
но для этого у меня вот это это всё
After Covid passed, this habit
после ковида прошло привычка такая
appeared. I always have
появилась Я вот у меня есть всегда в
gel in my car. Well,
машине гель Ну антисептик
show me the antiseptic. Now wait, give me the car,
показывай ль Сейчас подожди дай машину
at least since then I’ve always had
хотя бы я вот с тех пор всегда вот как
the anti-gel, as if Covid had passed for a long time.
бы уже ковид прошёл давно антигель у
there, it’s not a store
туалет сходил там в магазин не магазин
all the time with your
постоянно
hands It’s a habit, it’s already nothing And
руки Привычка уже всё уже уже ничего И
by the way, it helps I have
кстати помогает я 3 года не сглазить
n’t been sick with anything for 3 years after Covid In general, I’ve
ничем не болел после ковида Вообще ни
never been sick with anything, can you imagine That’s
разу ничем не болел представляешь
cool, yeah  I myself am
Прикольно да Я сам в
shocked by this g gel, are you just smearing your hands
шоке этим г гелем эти только руки мажешь
or not, well, what are you doing? Well, I’ll already anoint the house there.
или не ну там-то ты что Ну там я уже дом
Well, you’re kidding me, okay, there
помажу Ну ты прикалываешься коне кру там
you go, as usual, you come shower, as you
Ты как обычно приходишь душ как
think, you take everything, and you wash everything. Well, you
полагаешь принимаешь всё моешь Ну ты
touched him with dirty hands,
грязными руками его трогал то
maybe plan  because medicine
может плане потому что медициной
has proven
доказано
that during everyday life, so to speak, a person
что во время так сказать быта человек
can touch his
может касаться своего
face many thousands of times without noticing it,
лица много тысяч раз не замечая этого
well, that is, he scratched his nose and
самого ну то есть там нос почесал ещё
something else, well, that is, well, that is  like
что-то ну то есть ну то есть вот так вот
this And this is what I remember very strongly
Вот и вот это вот я очень сильно
Since then, after every one
запомнил С тех пор у меня После каждых
of these, I was sick with Covid, by the way, I
Таких вот Я же болел ковидом тоже кстати
also had Covi.
тоже переболел Кови
Well, in a mild form, thank
Ну в лёгкой форме слава
God, that’s
Богу
the same, but nevertheless, Since then,
вотже но тем не мени С тех пор у меня
it kind of got into my head  in a habit of
как бы вошло это в привычку
Independence I can even
а Независимости Я даже вот могу
say hello to people Yes, I said hello
поздороваться с людьми Да поздоровался
then, as if not offending them, out of quiet
потом как бы не оскорбляя их по тихой
sadness I went with my hands
грусти пошёл руки
profile Now wait Yes, I have one like that
профил Сейчас подожди Да у меня такая
Listen and  you’re already home You arrived,
есть Слушай а это ты уже домой Приехал
yes, it turns out by taxi Well, I’m at home
да получается на такси Ну я у дома да
and look at this garbage You see
вот смотри вот такой фигню Вот видишь
This is this garbage I always have it in my car, I
Вот такая фигня У меня лежит в машине
take it like soap
всегда я вот так вот беру оно как и мыло
and like DEZ, well, yes, I understand and that’s it
и как ДЕЗ это ну ну да понял и всё вот
so OP Listen, I’m interested in what
так вот оп Слушай а мне интересно как у
your roads look like, you can take a ride and
вас дороги выглядят можешь проехаться
show me what your roads look like
показать мне как у вас дороги выглядят
bro Listen, I definitely won’t be able to take a ride
братан Слушай ну проехаться точно не
because I’m already drunk this time, and as
смогу потому что я уже пьяный это раз а
for the roads, I can tell you that
что касается дорог Это я тебе могу
very well.  I can speak for my region, I
отлично те могу сказать за свой регион я
can’t speak for our entire vast country.
не могу тека за всю страну необъятную
Here I won’t argue with you, but
нашу Тут я с тобой не буду спорить а что
as for my roads, where I work, where
касается моих дорог где я работаю Где
I ride, Yes, there are
катаюсь Да есть косяки Базара нет во
shoals. There are no shoals in the yards. There are shoals
дворах там косяки есть
there.  this is true This is purely true
Прикольно да это правда Это чисто правда
and every year every year here we have Look
и каждый год каждый год вот у нас Смотри
here is the city Yes in One short year
вот горо Да в Один в один короче год
one road was moved there well a
одну дорогу пересели там ну участок
different section that is and in general I look I have already
другой то есть и в целом я смотрю уже
passed Let’s say even from the twenty-second
прошёл Допустим даже с двадцать второго
years, if you take
года если взять
Listen, you can go with a camera and show
Слушай можешь пройти с камерой показать
what your houses look like,
как у вас выглядят дома
how the entrances of houses look. Yes, right now there is no Bazaar
как дома подъезды Да сечас Базара нет
for an excursion like this,
подо экскурсию такую
let’s not question, let me
сделаем давай не вопрос давай мне
always wonder what it all looked like in Russia
интересно всегда как в России выглядело
now. There is no Bazaar. Now wait,
это всё сейчас Базара нет Сейчас подожди
I’ll just look at it now. I
я только сейчас это
wonder how  the city of guns
посмотрю Интересно как город пушки
looks like now, wait, there’s no market bro,
выглядит сечас подожди Базара нет братан
of course
Конечно
I’ll show you everything, let’s go
покажу всё пошли
have a look, so everything’s closed, it’s not
смотреть так всё закрыл не
closed. Well, look, for example,
закрыл Ну вот смотри например
now Switch the camera right away Yes,
сейчас Переключай сразу камеру Да чтоб
turn the camera around so I can see in the wrong place,
камеру разверни чтобы я видел не там
look at it  you see, this is this, this is
смот это вот вот видишь вот это это вот
this house, this is not my house, I’m showing
это дом это не мой дом показываю
some kind of entrance, here’s the entrance to the entrance, like
какой-то подъезд вот вход в подъезд как
these And the entrance to the entrance, yes, I understand Or there are
эти А вход в подъезд да пойм Или есть
benches or
лавочки или
pure Damn, listen, well, of course you’re
чисто Блин слушай ну те ты конечно
generally handsome Of course, such a meticulous
вообще красавчик Конечно такой дотошный
type Well, I’m great  also doto that, to be
тип Ну молодец я тоже дото что если
honest, it’s Well look, even here in our
честно такое Ну смотри у нас даже вот в
houses you were sitting here, it’s even
домах ты сидел тыре стоит даже
the temperature of the weather Look now I’ll show
температура погоды Смотри сейчас покажу
you wow Well look Yes now wait
ничего себе Ну смотри Да сечас подожди
not in every one I’m lying not in every one  but in
не в каждом вру не в каждом но в
some houses there is and this is why so
некоторых домах есть а это для чего
that people look to go outside
чтобы люди смотрели выходить на улицу
or not, who the hell knows why
или нет фиг его знает для чего Вот
Look,
смотри
wait, it shows lights up 2 Gra Yes Wow, it’s
Подожди показывает светится 2 Гра Да Вау
cool so far the technology is normal in
прикольно пока нормальна технология
all houses
всех домах
December 11 2 Gra Yes, for sure
декабря 2 Гра А да точно
I’m stupid not in all houses of course  but well, it
Туплю не во всех домах конечно но ну
is present And the further the houses
присутствует И чем дальше дома
develop like new ones that are being built
развиваются как новы которые строится
almost everywhere, it’s already happening Well,
практически уже везде происходит Ну вот
I don’t know, fih knows how those brothers
вот я не знаю фих его знает как те брата
e show
е показать
those so everyone has a watch No, it’s not in front of the
те так у всех часы есть Нет это не перед
house, it’s on  at the entrance, here's the
домом это вот на подъезде вот козырёк
entrance canopy Well, who knows, I
подъезд Ну фиг его знает у меня
ask why he showed it, it's just cool,
спрашиваю Для чего показал просто круто
you thought maybe not, well, I just
ти думал может нет ну я тебе просто
showed you what's there, and it's really cool, not
показал к тому что есть а там уж круто
cool, who knows, why, I don't
не круто фиг его знает для чего я сам не
know why, Oh, by the way, not
знаю для чего О кстати а не
pharmacy not bro Rossi I don’t know horse
аптека не братан Росси Я не знаю коне
someone don’t tell va
кто-то не говори ва
Show
Покажи
me Show me the
е Покажи детскую
playground and the
площадку а детскую
playground Now
площадку Сейчас
wait Okay, I’ll go first and I’ll
подожди Ладно пойду тебе сначала е
show you and then where already  I’ll go get a beer
покажу а потом гда уже за пиво пойду
in a minute I’ll show you this site I’ll show you
сечас покажу это вот площадку тебе
now It’s
сейчас
not the best one, you
покажу Не самая она такая м
know, but it’s there,
знаеш но есть
wait Be patient, I’m already on my
подожди Потерпи уж я уж что-то
way and by the way there are such sites
иду и вот таких площадок кстати их
in almost every one that I’ll now
практически в каждом что я тебе сейчас
show you in almost every one, that is, the
покажу практически в каждом то есть
microdistrict where there  more than 7 de houses
микрорайон где там более п7 де домов там
they are there And where are all the people you walk alone
они есть А где все люди ты один ходишь
like in this like in that
как по этому как по закину тому
area And where are all the
району А где все
people where are all the people in their homes for a long time
люди где все люди по домам уже давно ты
you thought there was dancing here or something  Are
ты думал здесь что пляски танцы что ли
you satisfied now, what is it 10 o'clock
устраивают у вас сейчас сколько 10 часов
or 11
или 11
o'clock? Look, now we're going through this,
часов Смотри вот сейчас проходим это вот
Well, this is what it's like, what's the meaning of this,
Ну это такая э как его в смыс это ре
what kind of football playground is this?
какая это футбольная мелкая площадка
how else can I show you here?
площадке знаю Как как тебе тут ещё
I don’t know, buddy, what about you? Well, it’s
показать Я не знаю дружище а у вас Ну у
normal there, you have a
вас нормально там у вас есть вообще
police department so it’s not shorter,
отделение полиции чтобы короче не было
look, we even have a soft surface, you know, we have a
смотри у нас даже мягкое понимаешь у нас
soft coating so that children fall,
покрытие мягкое то чтобы дети падали
wow, here it is  the soft surface is really
вау ну вот оно мягкое покрытие реально
a swing with a children's slide
качели при вот детская горка отделение
police station yes Well of course everyone has it
полици да Ну конечно есть оно у всех
it's probably far away or
есть оно далеко наверное да далеко или
far away
бли
Listen, go on foot Quite a long time
Слушай ну пешком ийти Достаточно долго
How long is it about
Сколько по
15 minutes Well, it turns out the
времени минут 15 Ну да получается
bandits can do something here and the
бандиты могут тут что-то сделать и
police won't have time  Yes, show me, show me the
полиция не успеет Да слу А покажи покажи
shops, show me somewhere where
магазины Покажи где-то где больше
people are more active,
активность людей магазины
some shops, so listen, I’m now going to the wrong
какие-то Так слушай я сейчас иду не в ту
activity, first of all, all the shops are already
активность во-первых у нас уже магазины
closed at 11 o’clock,
все закрылись 11 часов
how is it in ODI?  That there are
как это в ОДИ Что
no 24-hour
нету круглосуточных
stores.
магазинов
Of course they exist, but I
есть Есть конечно же они есть но я туда
definitely won’t go there now because I’m
сейчас точно не пойду потому что я
far from
далеко от
them. I’m now going to one where they
них я сейчас иду в один чный где пиво
sell beer. Well, show me
продают А ну покажешь
for now. Here are these houses. In what year
пока Вот вот эти дома в каком году
were these new houses built? Well, I  I say
построили эти Новые дома Ну я же говорю
this is the sun, this is all, but you showed me the
это это ВС это всё но ты показал мне
new site Yes, you showed me the site in the
новую площадку Да ты показал площадку в
new building, I understand, yes Well, do you want to
новостройке я понял да А ну хочешь
show the old one now now
старенького показать сейчас сейчас
now those against the backdrop of the old one I’ll show this is the
сейчас те на фоне старенького покажу это
private sector here, well bro Well, it’s still
частный сектор здесь ну братан Ну всё же
being built, damn it, well  damn, of course
строится всё же блин ну блин ну конечно
we have an old one too, I don’t know, you
старенька у нас тоже есть я не знаю
see what’s missing, now I’m crossing
видишь что нет вот сейчас я перехожу вот
this old sector, and let’s climb
этот старенький сектор идёт а ну давай
through the old sector, well, the usual
по стареньком сектору лазим ну обычные
sectors are the residential sector there, I don’t know what
секторы жилой сектор там я не знаю как
else to call it, you see cars driving there,
это ещё называть там видишь машины ездят
you see houses like that  It’s not clear that there’s
Видишь дома такие непонятно
no point in thinking about Russia like that, it’s
тут зря так думать о России плохо
really bad, wait a minute
реально сечас
Hello, is it possible that a
Здраствуйте А можно
woman is selling light there or a man
светло там женщина продаёт или мужчина
isn’t, a
нет
man is damn
мужчина блин
interesting Maybe I’m interested Can I,
интересно Может мне интересно Можно я
as an American, ask him a couple of questions  I have
как американец задам ему пару вопросов Я
never communicated with the sellers. Do you want
никогда с продавцами не общался хочешь
Ask Ask yes Ask
Задай Спроси да Спросите
Give them they want to ask a couple of questions
Дайте вот те хотят задать пару вопросов
answer Hello, it won’t
отве Здравствуйте
be long in an hour so
будет сделан неболь поэтому Вызовите
Please call the police this is the man who is
пожалуйста полицию это человек который
coming Well he threatens what he wants to do
идт Ну он угрожает что хочет сделать
Please run call the
Пожалуйста вызовите бегом
police Glory to Ukraine Glory to
полицию Слава Украине Слава
Ukraine what kind of [ __ ] is this  asks And you,
Украине что это за фигня спрашивает А ты
you said Come in and now tell
ты говорил Зайди и сейчас скажи типа ку
me like, let’s do it for me,
сделаем ты мне сказа
look, I trusted you as
Вот смотри ты вот я тебе доверился как
a person, you called me and told me
человеку ты мне позвонил и сказал
you'll knock me off 10 rubles for what I say. You told me what you told me. You'll
скажу Ты мне сказал что ты мне сказал 10
knock off 10 rubles for what I say.
косарей скинешь за то что Я такое скажу
Hello, are you talking? What 10 rubles are you saying?
Алло ты несёшь Какие 10 косарей ты
in person Come on Who are you Who are you going to go to
чно Давай Кто ты такой Кому ты зайдёшь
now you say this this this guy is
сейчас говориш это это вот этот мужик
telling me Now we’ll go to this
мне говорит Сейчас мы к этому пойдём
tell him he told me He said  will pay
скажи он мне сказал Он сказал заплатит
me
мне
10, so you understand, you said that 10,000 Where is
10 вот ты понял ты сказал что 10.000 Где
my 10,000 We came to this, I said what
мои 10.000 Мы зашли к этому я сказал то
you demanded, you said now let’s get
что ты требовал ты сказал сейчас дойдём
to it in short, who sells
к этому короче который торгует
beer around the clock, like say what and I’ll
круглосуточно пивом типа скажеш что ти и
pay you 10,000 rubles,
Заплачу тебе 10.000 руб
well, where are
ну где 10.000
my 10,000 Well, you said  this is in the city of
моих Ну ты говорил вот это в городе
Pushkin I live In short I want it in the area here
Пушкина Я живу Короче хочу на районе тут
Come on no lower below no Here it is
Давай нет ниже ниже нет Вот вот она
in the middle  Yes, you said that even more
посередине да Ты же говорил что ещё
briefly you called him
короче на него вызывал
like al Where are my people now
типа ал Где мои тепер
What from America Dude I’m from Ukraine
та Какая с Америки Чувак я из Украины
misto Khmelnitsky we’re here
мисто Хмельницкий мы тут
like Slava Buda Yes the security service of
типа Слава буда Да служба безпеки
Ukraine is here with you And
Украины тут с вами працюе А
let the Russians say if they want to [ __ ] with it, look at
да скажет россияни хоче ебуд с то смотри
everything to me  told the address of this, he says
ты мне всё рассказал адрес этого говорит
everything in short, you
всё короче ты же всё
handed over everything Well, give it to this seller and the
сдал А ну дай вот этому продавцу а
seller is a man and I’ll talk to you before
продавец мужи да поговорю с тобой пока
he
он не
runs off with whoever you want  talk to the
убежал с кем ты хочешь поговорить с
seller whom you
продавцом которого ты
called names I'll be offended if you hear anything
обзывал я ты обидишься если что услышишь
canceling what he told you your
отменя того что он тебе сказал твой
address and that's all it's about to
адрес вот и всё ужа сейчас
come Yes Give him the phone Give him the
зайдёт Да Дай ему трубку Дай ему
phone what are you hiding from him now I'm
трубку что ты прячешься теперь от него я
not hiding from him first of all he works
от него не прячусь во-первых он работает
for  him people, have courage, I won’t
у него люди имей смелость я не буду
leave everyone now, I won’t leave everything for
бросать я не буду всё бросать чтобы ради
you, how do you like the joke, it
тебя как Как тебе шутка прикол
turned out to be a joke, what’s wrong with
получился прикол по чём такой с
the seller Well, of course, you twisted his skin,
продавцом Ну да ты ему конечно шкурку
I’m just  I’m not from America myself I’m
подвернул Я просто не я из Америки сам Я
from America I’m not from Ukraine I just
сам из Америки Я не из Украины просто
decided to have fun
решил поприкалываться
That’s what the American thing is
Вот вот в чём вот американская Вот
That’s the mentality that they don’t care about
именно менталитет чтоб плевать им на
everyone and everything And the fact that I’m a
всех и на всё А то что я
store and the
магазин
fact that I go to this store every
да то что я хожу в этот магазин каждый
day and you  m said and the fact that I go to him
день и ты м наговорил а то что я к нему
Yes and how would it be those in general yes that’s
хожу Да и как бы это те вообще да вот
it yes yes no one for me What
так вот да да мне так никого Какие
problems need to be solved yours about my
проблемы нужно решить свою про мои
problems Yes these are my problems these are your
проблемы Да это мои проблемы это твои
problems That’s why this is happening with Ukraine
проблемы Вот поэтому с Украиной это и
don’t meddle there  This  our
происходит не лезьте туда это наша
problem is you get in there no look we we
проблема туда лезете нене смотри мы мы
we are Americans Yes by the way this guy Was
мы американцы Да кстати этот мужик Был
he who was he problems who was who was
он кто был он проблемы кто был кто был
this
по национальности этот
guy's nationality Yes, what difference does it make who's
мужик Да какая разница кто
nationality Well he's not Russian I understand
национальность Ну он не русский Я понял
Yes well What's the difference nationality
Да ну Какая разницам национальность
what's the difference got it Don't look at me  It’s the
какая разница понял Не мне смотри вот по
same principle that war happens, you
такому же принципу и происходит война вы
climb in there. And I look, I just understood, by
туда лезете А я смотри я Я просто понял
the way, after children, you can sell
у Вас кстати после дети можно продавать
alcohol, why can you sell alcohol after 10:00 pm
алкоголь чего у вас после 10:00 вечера
Officially  no Well, now
алкоголь Официально нет Ну а теперь
look, you burned me the name of his
смотри я ты спалил мне название его
store and not officially you can yes yes Yes
магазина а не официально можно да да Да
you can sl That is, it turns out uh you can
можно ты сл То есть получается э можно
call the police like that the
позвонить да типа в полицию что тут
store sells alcohol Yes
магазин торгует алкогольным Да
illegal EU whatever you want you can of
нелегальном ЕС всё что хочешь можно
course you can Of course Why not
конечно можно Конечно Почему нет у
everyone has their own right Who wants to call
каждой есть своё право Кто хочет звонит
Who wants to not call Who wants to sell You
кто хочет не звонит кто хочет продаёт
want It’s not about that, but what do you think
хочеш Дело не в этом а как ты считаешь
whose
чей
Crimea is Russian of course Acha something You have
Крым российский конечно Ача чтото У тебя
different opinions or something Yes I So just in
другие мнени что ли Да я Так на всякий
case Yes Duma other opinions  I don’t
случай Да Дума другие мнения что ли я не
understand, I just asked, we from the Turks, the
пойму Я спросил просто мы у турк нас
Turks gave us at one time for this Crimea.
турки дали в своё время за этот Крым
Listen, and then they took it back from them.
Слушай с а потом у них его обратно
Listen, what if, in short, for example, to
отжали Слушай а если Короче например к
this Tajik whom you went to
вот этому таджику к которому ты ходил
or who he was, and if to him  the police
или кто он был да если к нему полиция
will come and give him a nightmare because
будет приходить его кошмарит за то что
he sells alcohol in the evening, like they’ll say
он продаёт вечером алкоголь типа скажут
at the request of a guy from Yandex
по по заявке мужика с Яндек
taxi
такси
What okay, you didn’t understand okay By the way, we haven’t
Чего ладно ты не понял окей Кстати мы не
met What’s your name I’m
познакомились Как тебя зовут Меня
me a novel a novel  me, Andrey
меня роман роман меня вот Андрей
Vasilyevich And you, Roman Roman
Васильевич А тебя Роман Роман
Vyacheslavovich Roman Vyacheslavovich Romn
Вячеславович Роман Вячеславович ромн
Vyacheslavovich It’s cool,
Вячеславович Прикольно
he’s an Armenian, an Armenian
да он армянин армянин
Yes, Roman Vyacheslavovich and an Armenian Yes, I understand,
Да Роман Вячеславович и армянин Да понял
now we’ll write it down, we’ll
сейчас запишем
remember it Well, your face is not
запомним Ну у тебя какое-то лицо не
Russian,
русское
you’re not me,
ты сам не меня
who am I like then if not
Да на кого же я похож тогда если не
Russian
русский
interested in someone else's opinion Well, it seems to me
интересно чужое мнение Ну мне кажется
that you are Ukrainian, you probably have a Ukrainian
что ты украинец у тебя украинская
surname
фамилия наверное
Yes Listen, well, I’ll tell you this Yaya I don’t
Да Слушай ну я тебе так скажу Яя не
know, I’ll tell you only one thing that I have,
знаю я тебе скажу только одно что у меня
for example, a mother, a father, where they were born, where they
вот например мама папа где родились
grew up, it was all the territory
росли выросли это всё было территория
of Russia and their grandparents also
России и бабушки дедушки их тоже
concern them. Well, how about your surname,
касаются Хорошо как вот у тебя фамилия
Russian or not Russian, Yurov like Yurov
русская или не русская Юров
Yurov, it turns out Yurov Yes, I
Юров ты получается Юров Да
understand, in my opinion, Russian Well, Yurov rut is a
понял по-моему русская Ну да Юров руть
surname, in fact, I understand,
это фамилия на самом деле понимаю
yes And by the way, did you register about the
да А ты кстати зарегистрировал о там
police there or what and the police were
полиция или что а полиция
driving the police no what is the police from where to the
ехала полиция нет како полиция откуда на
police or what is it  I was driving,
полиция или что это ехало да я что там
maybe I drove there soon, maybe I went to someone soon,
проехал может скоро кому-то
Maybe the police are singing But
поехал Может полиция поет А ты
you don’t listen, but you do
получается ты не слушай а ты получается
n’t turn out I registered as an individual
не Зарегистрировался как индивидуальный
entrepreneur, I’m self-employed, so I’m
предприниматель я самозанятый так
self-employed, this is the individual
самозанятый это ти индивидуальный
entrepreneur I should have
предприниматель должен был
My car is not registered in
У меня машина зарегистрирована не на
my name as an
меня как
individual entrepreneur But in
ИП А на
who is a
кого на
relative, okay And listen, but you have
родственника ладно А слушай а вот у вас
this new area, like it turns out to be in
этот новый район типа это получается в
Pushkin, like what am I looking at, a bunch of very
Пушкина типа что это я смотрю куча очень
new buildings, this is really a new
новостроек это реально новый
area, that’s what I’ve seen now, the old
район вот то что сейчас видел уже старый
area,
район
yeah, that’s what it’s now  I saw this is not a new
угу вот то что сейчас видел это не новый
district, this is already Believe me, this is a district for
район это уже Поверь мне это район уже
6-7 years already, but when will I show you the New district
6-7 а вот Новый район когда тебе покажу
Damn, well, I don’t know Let’s see what
Блин ну ну я не знаю Увидим как
this district of yours is called,
называется вот этот твой
Berezhok street Berezhok, what is this? And what does
Бережок Бережок это что есть такая А что
such a street as Berezhok
означает улица такая Бережок
Berezhkovskaya mean?  the embankment in Moscow is
Бережковская набережная в Москве такое
Berezhok. Why is there such a Berezhok embankment in Moscow?
Бережок А почему в Москве такая
There are such streets in Moscow as
набережная в Москве такие улицы есть
Berezhkovskaya embankment. I
Бережковская набереж откуда такое
don’t
понятие не
know where this concept comes from. Berezhok
знаю Бережок
Pushkino even  I want to find on the map
Пушкино даже я на карте хочу найти
the street Iev is Ivanteevka
улица иев есть Ивантеевка
Yes, it’s a
Да ште
different topic, but what’s the difference,
другая тема да какая разница-то на
it’s one thing on Pushkin, but you can see it right away
Пушкина это одно а у тебя видишь сразу А
But now Go to Pushkin Look if
вот теперь Зайди в пушкины Посмотри если
you’re interested in the new area Here’s Jock
тебе новый район интересен Вот вот жок
Nuri, look Yes, the
Нури посмотри Да сеча
section shows what O  In short, yes,
стро что показывает О я короче прям да у
you have Berezhok street like there, it
вас вот э улица Бережок типа там
really shows these high-rise buildings, it’s
действительно показывает эти многоэтажки
really cool there Pyaterochka You have
реально классно там Пятёрочка У вас есть
yes yes yes Pyaterochka Disi in one area
да да да Пятёрочка Диси на одном районе
only  Some kind of Venice I see
только Венеция какая-то смотрю
Yes, it’s
Да
cool Yes, it’s not an ordinary ordinary,
прикольно Да не это обычный обыкновенный
like a city damn district, let’s say there’s
как бы городской блин округ скажем так
nothing like that there at all, no, I
там ничего такого вообще нет не не я
see that the layout is very beautiful,
смотрю что планировка очень красивая у
these courtyards have really beautiful courtyards
этих дворов реально красивые дворы
before, when I came here, there
раньше когда я сюда заезжал здесь такие
were such barracks at all.  I can imagine what it
Бараки были вообще ты не представляю что
was like here. It’s literally 8-7 years ago,
здесь было Это буквально лет 8-7 назад
it’s cool, here on this bank there were
прикольно здесь на этом бережке были
just Barracks where, in short, no lights
просто Бараки где Короче ни фонари не
were on, and the police didn’t even come here
горели ни милиция сюда даже не ездила
because the police were afraid to come here.
потому что боялась милиция сюда ездить
Yes, this  it was a fact, now everything is
Да это было это фак сейчас всё
different and so throughout the
по-другому и так по всей
country, look, and this
стране так смотри а это ты
is you, well, Berezhok, I see it’s beautiful, and
получается ну Бережок я вижу красиво а
you already went to this street which is
ты уже ходил на эту улицу которая
Kolkhoznaya, the dates are already at the kolkhoz count.
Колхозная даты уже по колхозно
It goes legally to the address of
кол Она идёт юридически по адресу
the kolkhoz, only in a new building.
колхозна только новостройке
Cool, yes, yes  don’t make it look
стоят Прикольно да да да не краси там
interesting there, it’s already a private sector
интересно так там уже это частный сектор
And here it’s really like that yes yes yes yes I
А тут реально такое да да да да я под
wake up to the roosters in the morning the roosters
петухами просыпаюсь по утрам петухи
you know how people crow there but
знаешь как кукарекают там же люди же
they don’t  to get out of the habit of rural life
никак не отвыкнуть от сельской жизни У
They still have roosters and hens there and I
них там до сих пор петухи и куриц и там
don’t know that everyone has everything there
не знаю что там у всех всё есть
Regardless of where they
Независимости от того где они
want They will have roosters and hens
хотят они Петухов и куриц они будут
I’m
иметь я
here and they have roosters and hens Yes I
вот а у них петухи и курицы Да
understand And this works out for them  you really
понял А это получается у вас реально
exist, it’s just that here in the USA all the stores
есть просто вот у нас в США все магазины
close at 8 pm at 8 pm you
закрываются в 8 вечера в 8 вечера уже
can’t buy anything
ничего не купишь
at all, we don’t have any, I
вообще нет у
take it in general Moscow Yeah
кае беру вообще в целом Москву Угу
Moscow region all the stores are open
Московская область все магазины работают
until 11:00 there are 24-hour stores
до 11:00 есть круглосуточные магазины
there, Pyaterochka chain stores, but there is no alcohol for sale there.
там Пятёрочки сетевые но алкоголь там в
Well, yes, there is alcohol and tobacco, no tobacco,
нету Ну да алкоголь и табак нет табак
no tobacco, yes, there is a sale of tobacco. There
нет табак есть да продажа табака есть
is no market. And there is no alcohol, alcohol from 9
Базара нет А алкоголь нет алкоголь с 9 и
to 11 in general in the country, in fact, there
до 11 вообще в стране по факту не
is no less
е Мень
cut.  Well, this one turns out Well, it’s the Armenians who
уреза Ну а этот получается Ну это армян
work all night long, he doesn’t get enough sleep
целую ночь работает он что не высыпается
at all, yes yes Listen, it turns out that
вообще да да Слушай а получается так что
in such an incident some pavilions are created,
в таком казус создаются некоторые
some
павильон некоторые магазинчики
24-hour shops where they sell alcohol No,
круглосуточные где алкоголь продают Не
well  this is taco I just have
ну это тако Просто я имею
in mind I wrote the night he worked there for the night
вду писал ночь он ночь поработал у него
also a 12 hour shift for example
там также 12 часо смена например
there, well, that is, well, like that, of course.
там ну то есть ну вот так вот ну конечно
Listen, in America, where you
Слушай а у вас е в Америке где ноч
can’t buy alcohol at night or something? In
нельзя купить алкоголь что ли Вообще
general, at all. But wait, that is, this  it turns out
вообще А подожди То есть это получается
that somehow you went out into some basement,
у него это как-то ты в какой-то подвал
it’s really a store he has with a
выходил это у него реально магазин с
sign like with the name Well, something like that
вывеской типа с названием Ну типа того
Well, what is it called there products or
Ну как он называется там продукты или
what are the products banal products No, well,
как продукты банальные продукты Да не ну
everyone there calls it something, for example there
его там все как-то называют например там
name or whatever the name of this store is
наме или как Как называется этот магазин
not called at all, look, I’ll
никак не называется смотри я тебе
explain to you that’s what concerns night
объясняю вот что касается ночных
sales of
торговли по
alcohol, but to be honest, I myself am against
алкоголю вот если честно я сам против
such
таких
sales. I hope sooner or later we will
продаж Я надеюсь рано или поздно Мы к
come to this, that it will be a ban for a
этому придём что это будет Запрет чтобы
person to go out at night and not be able to go anywhere.
человек вышел ночью и нигде не смог
buy At this stage in our country
купить На данном этапе в нашей стране
this is practiced, that is, that is, it is
это практикуется то есть то есть
practiced How do all the chain
практикуется Каким образом все сетевые
stores everything, that is, everything is closed, but there are,
магазины все то есть всё закрыто но есть
nevertheless, there are
тем не менее есть точки
24-hour outlets that can sell
круглосуточные которые могут продать
you this is alcohol, this is this fact, I didn’t buy
тебе это алкоголь это есть это фак я не
It’s not
сказа оже ещ продукты продаёт Это же не
just alcohol, it’s true, but if a person
только алкоголь правда но если человеку
needs bread and lard and whatever you want, it’s
нужно хлеб и сало и что хочешь это
usually
обыч
delicious, h there in di there And they have because
вкусно ч там в ди там А у них потому что
their suppliers are
у них поставщики
different, their suppliers from such
другие у них поставщики у таких
stores are not these  which
магазинов не вот эти которые
there I’m not sure about, it’s that he has a store in the
там я что-то не по это у него магазин в
private sector,
частном секторе
well, actually, yeah, well, like, he’s not in
выходит ну фактически Да ну типа он не в
a high-rise building, he’s like, in a private house, like,
многоэтажке он типа в частном доме типа
or look, he’s standing on
или смотри он стоит на территории
Mat’s territory, this store is for him
Мэта этот магазинн ему
t Probably this stall  You see,
т Наверно этому ларь Понимаешь
this store has been here for a long, long time,
этот магазин очень давно-давно здесь
so wait, is this a
существует так подожди это ларёк
separate stall or is it in this in the house this is a
отдельный или это в этом в в доме это
stall, a banal
ларёк банальный
stall Well, if you understand the word
ларёк Ну если понимаешь слово
stall, tent, tent, such a small
ларёк палатка палатка такая небольшая
tent, there is
палатка выст там есть
everything cool there,
всё прикольно
Yes, it’s cool, maybe not cool, but
Да вот прикольно может не прикольно но
you know I  Sometimes I’m inclined to
ты знаешь я вот иногда склоняюсь к такой
think that it’s time to ban myself from this
мысле что пора запрещать себе вот эту
[ __ ]. We have a lot of stalls like this around the
фигню У нас таких много ларьков по
country. According to the law, you can’t buy alcohol from us
стране по закону у нас алкоголь не
after that, paragraph But here they are  there
купишь после о всё абзац Но вот такие
are stalls. It’s terrible, but there are
ларьки есть Ужас а есть такие вот
those like that, that’s what you just saw,
которые вот что ты вот сейчас видел
yes, yes, I think this is a drawback,
да да это я считаю это недостаток
yes, on the one hand, on the
да с одной
other hand, you know, sometimes it happens,
с другой стороны Ты знаешь иногда бывает
damn, you go out at night and
блин выйдешь ночью а сигарет купить
there’s nowhere to buy cigarettes, yes, here I am, for example, I don’t
негде нету да Вот я вот например мне не
need pi and cigarettes  you need and what to do,
нужно пи а сигареты нужно и что делать
you understand T is a double-edged sword As they
понимаешь Т палка о двух концах Как
say, yes Oh look, I opened it right on Google
говорится да О смотри я прям в Google
maps, you can see your area
картах открыл прям видно ваш район
is actually a kindergarten, here is Berezhok street
реально детский садик вот улица Бережок
10 - This is a kindergarten Yes yes there is
10 - Это детский садик Да да есть
really cool  really cool
реально круто реально круто
Bro, you’re not just opening a
Братан ты вот не только вавку открывай
new one in Pushkin, you’re opening a new Pushkin in Pushkin Open there and
ты во Пушкину новоя Пушкина Открой там
see how I’ll tell you more in all
посмотри как я тебе больше скажу по всем
regions of Moscow Such a global construction
регионам Москвы такая глобальне стройка
is going on for me as a driver, as a taxi driver, it’s
идёт меня как водителя как таксиста это
annoying So because there are constant
напрягает Так что потому что постоянные
traffic jams, constant repairs of some kind I already
пробки постоянно ремонты какие-то Я уже
I’m spitting from this Bazaar, we don’t have a
плююсь от этого Базара нет у нас город
Nazi city. Listen, I
нази Слушай я на карте на карте что-то
can’t see this store on the map, it’s probably a
не видно этого магазина Он наверное
new store, some kind of store in this one in the
новый какой-то магазин на этой на
pictures  there is no
картинках нету
store and it won’t be you on the map of
магазина а его не будет тебя на карте
this store There are no photographs there, there
этого магазина Нет там фотографии там
are photographs like, well,
вот есть фотографии как ну типа
photographs of the entire area and this store is not there
фотографии всего района и там нету этого
And you are not there And where will it be from there,
магазина А тебя его не А откуда он там
it is not an official store No, well, the
будет он не официальный магазинчик Не ну
entrance would be visible there,
там видно вход было бы
like  I don’t care, it’s a store,
типа да пофигу это магази
it’s just
это просто
Lark, it’s just a stall, it’s just a tent there, 3
Ларк просто ларёк просто палатка там 3
on 5 m. What a Well, people come in, I
на 5 ме Какая Ну люди заходят я даже
don’t even see a stall there on these now, and you
ларька не вижу туда на этих сейчас а ты
won’t find it at all.
его не найдёшь вообще у него Адрес
You know which address is going to score
знаешь какой идёт забить
three Now
три Сейчас
wait, either Kolkhoznaya 3A
подожди либо Колхозная 3А
or Berezhok
либо Бережок
1A now, in my opinion, Berezhok oh, not in
1А сечас вот вот по-моему Бережок о не
my opinion, everything is not Berezhok OA, in my opinion,
по-моему всё нет Бережок ОА по-моему
Berezhok ody a Well, call and see what it
Бережок оди а Ну зови посмотри что
gives Berezhok one finds so oh, yes
даст Бережок один находит так о вот да
Now we’ll look at this one, yes there
Сейчас мы посмотрим вот один вот вот да
is  this is food there and it says 821
есть это во там продукты и написано 821
on this
на этом
on Wednesday Yes this is it yes there are bars on the
на сре Да это оно да такой там рештки на
windows iron door no well there is no such thing
окнах желез дверь не ну там нет такого
Nothing I don’t
Ничего я не
know Well he  such a color, such a
знаю Ну он такого цвета такого
pinkish Yes, pinkish yellow ato In short,
розоватого Да розовато жёлто ато Короче
this store has already existed, you know, about
этот магазин уже существует знаешь лет
20 years, so in short, there is a big sign for
20 так короче там большая вывеска
products like this on it
продукты такая на нём Да нет там уже
Yes, no, there hasn’t been any of this for a long time, well, I understand, it’s not the case, it’s not well, it’s
нет ну Поня ну не случа не не ну
written that it’s open until 21,
написано что он до 21 работает
of course it’s written Well  it's there
конечно написано Ну там он
24 hours a day Well, yes, it
круглосуточный А ну да это это
works out. It's just the street, this
получается Он как раз улица вот эта
collective farm goes across the road to the private
колхозна идёт через дорогу частный
sector, and across the road is this little shop, yes yes yes yes yes
сектор А через дорогу этот магазинчик да
yes, it's in such a vacant lot
да да да да да он на таком пустыре
around it, there's a parking lot where
вокруг него стоянка паркуются
cars are parked  Yes, and I say it’s so empty, there are
машины Да а говорю он на на таком пуст
cars parked around it, yes yes yes yes.
вокруг него паркуются машины да да да да
Cool
Прикольно да
yes. By the way, there’s a problem here with parking spaces. I
Вот кстати с парковочными местами Здесь
can even complain to
проблема тут уже могу даже пожаловаться
the Americans. I don’t know how it is with you with
американцам я не знаю как у вас с
parking spaces in residential areas, but
парковочными местами в жилых районах но
we have a problem. Listen, it turns out  I look
у нас беда Слушай а получается я смотрю
at the photographs next to these shops,
на фотографиях рядом с этим магазинчиков
some kind of two-story old house.
какой-то двухэтажный такой старый дом
In general, it’s no longer there, no longer, yes, I understand.
Вообще его уже нету уже нету да понял
Yeah. This is an old photo, this seems to be an old
Ага Это старое фото это походу старое
photo. I understand it’s already in Google maps, old
фото Поня его уже в Google картах старые
photos. Well, the store  I understand yes flock f I
фото Ну магазин Понял да стае ф Я же
told you before that in general in
тебе до этого и говорил что вообще на
this place the bank is where I
этом месте бережке вот где вот я тебе
just showed you those houses All this
сейчас показывал те дома Всё вот это
Okay everything is
Ладно всё
I don’t care what’s in short damn in
му Мне всё равно что там короче блин в
your bank I needed to find out the
вашем бережке Мне нужно было узнать
address of this store Yes  where is this
адрес этого магазина Да где это там
Armenian selling vodka at night? Yes, it’s
армянин ночью водку продаёт Да
illegal to call Poly,
нелегально чтоб позвонить Поли полицию
tell the police, listen to me. Hello, I’m Roman
сказать слушай меня Здравствуйте я Роман
Vyacheslavovich Yurov. I want to say that they
Вячеславович Юров хочу сказать тут
sell alcohol illegally. Please
нелегально торгуют алкоголем Прошу
take
принять
action.
меры
Ukraine, sorry for me.  It took so long, there
Украине сори что я так долго его тянул
was no need for a localization But Crimea is
не нужно было локали Зато что Крым - это
Russia I think we will do something
Россия Я думаю мы сделаем что-то такое
for the soul for this, everything that happened today and
для души за это всё что сегодня было и
for the fun in the store Let's like the squeak
за прикол в магазине Давайте лайк писка
comment on Telegram right now the VN axis
комент на Telegram прям зараз ось ВН
apok tse more and more  respectfully YouTube took
апок це дуже и дуже важливо YouTube заня
us through skarg or in your ban and I
нас через скарг ор в твый бан и дуже
don’t show too many videos to people, I don’t
багато вдео не показую людям вчасно не
show information about streams for this
показуе информация про стримы тому для
purpose  Shchob mi Mali operational link
того щоб ми Мали оперативный звязок
write directly at the same time and while there in telegra
пишиться прямо зараз а пок там в телегра
okrim video shchezh va and kos information and
окрим видео ще теж ва и кос информация и
we will blame you trimati postiyny
мы повинни з вами тримати постийний
operational link nezalezhno in that chi
оперативный звязок незалежно в того чи
show you about it YouTube Glory to Ukraine
покаже вам про це YouTube Слава украини
subscribe N
подпишись N